RUSS TRACY

South Weber, UT 84405

Phone: (801) 628-9257 | E-mail: russ_tracy@comcast.net
LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/russtracy | GitHub: https://github.com/RussTracy
Portfolio: https://russtracy.github.io/Russ-Portfolio/

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer who has been consistently praised as quality-oriented by my co-workers and management. Strong knowledge of HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery. Experienced in working with other developers remotely to accomplish desired results. Have consistently demonstrated teamwork, problem-solving and interpersonal abilities in every aspect of my previous role as a web developer.

Skills

Languages: HTML - JavaScript - CSS - Git - MySQL - jQuery - Bootstrap - API's - Ajax - Node - Express.js - C# - MVC.net - XML - XSL - JSON

Applications: Microsoft Suite - Adobe Photoshop - Visual Studio - WalkMe - Visio

Experience

Web Developer II Marriott International

2017 - 2020 Salt Lake City, UT

- Developed a complex software application to track VDN numbers for the telecommunication department.
- Engineered PCI redaction triggers using 3rd party software, preventing recording of personal information during customer phone calls.
- Designed and implemented WalkMe solutions to enhance ongoing user training.
- Conducted review testing of various web applications for responsiveness and clarity.

Web Developer I Marriott International

2011 - 2017 Salt Lake City, UT

- Converted 22,000 page information application to new web platform, providing a 10% increase in efficiency.
- Redesigned information web application to include JavaScript/jQuery and SQL Database functionality, resulting in improved dissemination of complex hotel information.
- Conducted QA testing over course of web development lifecycle, resulting in increased site functionality.
- Developed new scripts to allow for better navigation of current websites, resulting in a 5% drop in call times.

Intranet Content Administrator Marriott International

2001 - 2011 Salt Lake City, UT

- Reviewed incoming change requests to verify content with company guidelines, increasing consistency of information provided to guests.
- Modified 50+ articles per week with a 24 hour turnaround requirement, increasing accuracy of information provided to guests.
- Upgraded an 15,000 page internal information system to a web-based application using HTML and inline CSS, assisting 1,000+ customers in several satellite offices world wide.
- Established streamlined CSS files to improve efficiency of web-based information systems, resulting in 75% reduction in written code.

Projects

Can I Bike

Web app providing information on city bike rentals as well as local weather conditions.

Role: Setting up API calls to import data into site.

GitHub - https://github.com/hunterstrunk/can-i-bike

Site - https://hunterstrunk.github.io/can-i-bike/

Technology: HTML, CSS (Bulma), JavaScript, Open Weather API, City Bikes API

Education

October 2020 - April 2021

University of Utah - Full Stack Web Development Certificate

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS

2007 - 2009

Western Governors University - Information Technology

Licenses & Certifications

Certified Internet Web Professional Web Foundations Associate (CIW)

Issued Aug 2007 (Western Governors University)
Credential ID 306020

Certified Internet Web Professional JavaScript Specialist (CIW)

Issued Sep 2009 (Western Governors University)

Credential ID 306020

Certified Internet Web Professional v5 Associate (CIW)

Issued Aug 2007 (Western Governors University)
Credential ID 306020

CompTIA A+

Issued Jul 2009 (Western Governors University)
Credential ID COMP001008900888